Zach Cohen

User Experience Researcher & Designer I zach-cohen.com

My background and work experience are focused on how we interact with the world around us. Through design and research, I am mindful of the entire product lifecycle and its business impact. My goal is to help improve systems for groups in the life sciences dealing with precision health and medicine solutions for genetic or autoimmune diseases.

Experience

Bentley University User Experience Center

Research and Design Associate | 2021 - 2022

- Worked with Boston Scientific, Ginkgo Bioworks, Custom Medical.
- Qualitative and quantitative data analysis, insight synthesis, presentation of findings and recommendations.

Integrate Inc.

Product Designer | 2019 - 2021

- Established a design system guild to guide best practices and overall progression.
- Partnered with product management to conduct discovery and define software features.
- Led design and product-informed strategy for several product development teams.
- Prototyped, user tested, and collaborated with engineering to implement and ship designs.
- Developed user research initiatives to improve integration of research into the product development process.

InEight

Interaction Designer (Contract) | 2018 - 2019

- Translated design vision established through research to update legacy product.
- Worked closely with product and development teams to add and refine product features.
- Led user experience optimization alongside key stakeholders and product management.

Nucleus Marketing Lab

User Researcher (Contract) | 2018 - 2018

- Helped recognize user behavior and re-frame product development goals through qualitative and quantitative research and analysis.
- Used accumulated data to help provide brand strategy insight for both regional and national companies.

References available upon request | zachtylercohen@gmail.com | 480-444-8097

Education

Bentley University

M.S. – Human Factors in Information Design Expected Graduation 2022

Designlab

Certificate - User Experience Design Graduated 2018

Woodbury University

B.A. – Interdisciplinary Studies (Psychology and Interior Architecture Emphases)

Graduated 2017

Skills

Qualitative and Quantitative Research

Usability Testing

High Fidelity Prototyping

User Interface Design

Information Architecture

Software and applications

<u>Design</u>

Figma HTML Adobe XD CSS

Sketch JavaScript
InVision GitHub

Research

Framer

Dovetail Qualtrics

Pendo Survey Monkey

Mural

FullStory

Topics of Interest

Healthcare/Personal Health AI/ML

Precision Health/Medicine Data Ethics